Guide to the Yale Cabaret Scripts and Ephemera Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Yale Cabaret Scripts and Ephemera Collection
1974-2009
DRA 34
Yale University Arts Library
4.59
(11 boxes)
This collection contains scripts and ephemera from the Yale Cabaret.
Yale Cabaret
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Yale Cabaret Scripts and Ephemera Collection was housed in the former Drama Library until its transfer to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library in 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains scripts produced by and ephemera pertaining to the Yale Cabaret.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale Cabaret is a theater managed and produced by Yale School of Drama students. The Cabaret stages about 20 productions per year. It provides a unique performance setting which includes under 100 reconfigurable seats. The theater produces two performances per evening, serving food and beverage. These productions include adaptations of published plays, student-written plays, and collaboratively devised pieces.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Scripts. II. Ephemera.
Scripts (documents); Theater programs; Newsletters; Yale Cabaret
- Scripts, Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically by year of production, then alphabetically by author's last name.
  - When Dinah Shore Ruled the Earth, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Insomnia, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Taking Care of Business or, A Tic in Their Tongues, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - The Resurrection of Lady Lester, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Deadline, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - Celina or, The Child of Mystery, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - The Hostage, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Son of Arlecchino, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Holding Patterns, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Korea, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Suicidal Romance, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Jungle Toons, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Rhinestones and Paste, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - The Flaming Carrot, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - The Lou Pontel Handbook, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - Pambo, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Self Torture and Strenuous Exercise in America, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
  - The Lesson, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
  - Maria, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Home, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Medal of Honor Rag, 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Kennedy's Children, 2001-2002 (Box 3)
  - Without/Sin, 2004-2005 (Box 3)
- Ephemera
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes ephemera such as posters, programs, photographs, clippings, advertisements, and newsletters pertaining to the Yale Cabaret.
  Arranged chronologically by year and then by month and day of performance.
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1971-1972, 3 (Box 4, Folder 1a)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1973-1974, Folder 1b: 24 items; Folder 2: 14 items; Folder 3: 24 items (Box 4, Folder 1b-3)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1974-1975, Folder 4: 18 items; Folder 5: 33 items (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1975-1976, 45 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1976-1977, Folder 7: 27 items; Folder 8: 20 items (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1977-1978, Folder 1: 26 items; Folder 2: 13 items (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1978-1979, Folder 9: 20 items; Folder 10: 18 items (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1979-1980, Folder 3: 16 items; Folder 4: 22 items (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1980-1981, Folder 5: 39 items; Folder 6: 47 items (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1981-1982, Folder 11: 51 items; Folder 12: 44 items (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1982-1983, Folder 13: 40 items; Folder 14: 31 items (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1983-1984, Folder 15: 27 items; Folder 16: 27 items (Box 5, Folder 15-16)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1984-1985, Folder 17: 22 items; Folder 18: 21 items; Folder 19: 26 items (Box 5, Folder 17-19)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1985-1986, Folder 20: 25 items; Folder 21: 20 items (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1986-1987, Folder 22: 25 items; Folder 23: 18 items (Box 6, Folder 22-23)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1987-1988, Folder 24: 20 items; Folder 25: 16 items; Folder 26: 24 items; Folder 27: 24 items (Box 6, Folder 24-27)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1988-1989, Folder 28: 24 items; Folder 29: 28 items (Box 6, Folder 28-29)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1989-1990, Folder 30: 22 items; Folder 31: 21 items (Box 6, Folder 30-31)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1990-1991, Folder 32: 16 items; Folder 33: 16 items; Folder 34: 13 items (Box 6, Folder 32-34)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1991-1992, Folder 35: 26 items; Folder 36: 20 items (Box 7, Folder 35-36)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1992-1993, Folder 37: 23 items; Folder 38: 16 items; Folder 39: 21 items (Box 7, Folder 37-39)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1993-1994, Folder 40: 24 items; Folder 41: 18 items (Box 7, Folder 40-41)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1994-1995, Folder 42: 20 items; Folder 43: 15 items; Folder 44: 18 items (Box 7, Folder 42-44)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1995-1996, Folder 45: 11 items; Folder 46: 22 items; Folder 47: 23 items (Box 7, Folder 45-47)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1996-1997, Folder 48: 33 items; Folder 49: 10 items (Box 7, Folder 48-49)
    Folder 48 includes a Yale Cabaret promotional toothbrush.
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1997-1998, Folder 50: 18 items; Folder 51: 13 items; Folder 52: 13 items (Box 8, Folder 50-52)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1998-1999, Folder 53: 22 items; Folder 54: 17 items; Folder 55: 8 items (Box 8, Folder 53-55)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 1999-2000, Folder 56: 27 items; Folder 57: 31 items (Box 8, Folder 56-57)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 2000-2001, Folder 58: 25 items; Folder 59: 20 items; Folder 60: 21 items (Box 8, Folder 58-60)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 2001-2002, Folder 61: 24 items; Folder 62: 22 items; Folder 63: 20 items; Folder 64: 14 items; Folder 65: 1 item (Box 8, Folder 61-65)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 2002-2003, Folder 66: 22 items; Folder 67: 12 items; Folder 68: 16 items (Box 8, Folder 66-68)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 2003-2004, Folder 69: 26 items; Folder 70: 29 items; Folder 71: 21 items (Box 9, Folder 69-71)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 2004-2005, Folder 72: 29 items; Folder 73: 32 items (Box 9, Folder 72-73)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 2005-2006, Folder 74: 50 items; Folder 75: 32 items; Folder 76: 25 items; Folder 77: 25 items (Box 9, Folder 74-77)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 2006-2007, Folder 78: 42 items; Folder 79: 45 items; Folder 80: 30 items; Folder 81: 39 items; Folder 82: 34 items (Box 9, Folder 78-82)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 2007-2008, Folder 83: 26 items; Folder 84: 40 items; Folder 85: 75 items; Folder 86: 40 items; Folder 87: 25 items; Folder 88: 40 items (Box 10, Folder 83-88)
  - Yale Cabaret ephemera, 2008-2009, Folder 89: 28 items; Folder 90: 32 items; Folder 91: 25 items (Box 10, Folder 89-91)
  - Show posters, 2013-2014; 19 (Box 10, Folder 92)